(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.1",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
Tokino Sora
Ayunda Risu
Moona Hoshinova
Kobo Kanaeru
Rikka
Minase Rio
ヒトリ
Hitori (Alone)
愛されないことは
I knew best that...
私が一番知っていたの
...I was the one who wouldn't be loved.
それでもあなたはこの痛みに
Even so, you gave...
意味を与えてくれたから
...meaning to this pain.
壊れてしまう恋だとしても
Even if it's a love that will break...
信じたいと思ったの
...I wanted to believe in it.
ヒトリ
Alone
#iofiLucidDream
なんてんだよ
Why is it so?
あなたなら私のすべて
If it's you,
わかってくれる
you'll understand everything about me.
気がした
I felt that.
あなたを愛しすぎてしまう前に
Before I end up loving you too much,
あなたをすべて知る前に
Before I know everything about you.
空に願う
I pray to the sky,
遠く未来があるように
that there's a distant future.
今さらひとり泣いてるの？
Are you still crying alone now?
小さな私の手に
I overlapped with my small hands
重ねたあなたの大きな手
your big hands.
失いたくないと願うほど
The more I pray that I don't want to lose them,
苦しくなっていたの
the more painful it became.
こびりついた真紅な愛が
Before the clinging deep red love
消える前に
disappears,
あなたに会いたくて
because I want to see you,
目を閉じると
when I close my eyes,
巻き戻される最後の温かい夜
the last warm night is rewound.
優しいその目と
Those gentle eyes
優しいその言葉
and those gentle words,
すべて嘘じゃないと言いかせて
tell me that it's all not a lie.
これで最後の恋だと思ったの
I thought this was my last love.
だから繋ぎ止めていたかったのに
That's why I wanted to keep us tied together, and yet...
もうすべてわかってるから
Because I already understand everything.
もう私に近寄らないでよ
Don't come near me anymore.
果てしないこの苦しみまでも
To the point where I can even love
愛せるほど
this endless pain,
強い人はいないから
because there is no one that strong.
あなたを愛しているから
Because I love you,
ずっとあなたが私を忘れるまで
until you forget me forever.
星に願う
I pray to the stars,
どうか行かないで
please don't go.
ずっと私のそばにいてほしい
I want you to be by my side forever.
あなたを愛しすぎてしまう前に
Before I end up loving you too much,
あなたをすべて知る前に
Before I know everything about you.
空に願う
I pray to the sky,
遠く未来があるように
that there's a distant future.
今さらひとり泣いてるの
I'm crying alone now.
今もひとり泣いてるの
I'm still crying alone now.
Lagu Tanpa Huruf R
Song Without the Letter R
Lyrics, Music: Nadya Fatira
*Tidak ada huruf R dalam lirik lagu
*There is no letter R in the song lyrics
Ini kisahnya anak manusia
This is the story of a human child.
Kau bisa memanggilnya dengan nama Iofifteen
You can call her by the name Iofifteen.
Sebuah konsonan yang menyulitkan
A consonant that makes it difficult,
Membuat lidahnya bosan tak bisa ucapkan
making her tongue bored of not being able to say it.
Dia coba pahami setiap manusia
She tries to understand every human.
Punya hebat punya cacat
They have strengths, they have flaws.
Punya hebat punya cacat...
Has greatness, has flaws...
Dia coba nikmati hidup ini cuma sekali
She tries to enjoy this life only once
Dia
She
Hanya punya modal cinta
Only has love as her asset
Yang dia embuskan dalam setiap lagunya
Which she breathes into every one of her songs
Tak inginkan semua 'tuk suka dia
She doesn't want everyone to like her
Hanya ingin tuliskan lagu
She just wants to write a song
Tentang semua yang ada dalam hatinya
About everything that is in her heart
Bila tak suka tentu saja tak mengapa
If you don't like it, of course it's okay
Sejak kecil dia punya mimpi
Since she was little she has had a dream
Jadi musisi atau apapun di bidang seni
To be a musician or anything in the field of art
Tumbuh dewasa mulalah sudah
Growing up, it has begun
Keputusannya 'tuk dapatkan mimpinya
Her decision to achieve her dream
Dia coba pahami setiap manusia
She tries to understand every human being
Punya hebat punya cacat
Has greatness, has flaws
Dia coba nikmati hidup ini cuma sekali
She tries to enjoy this life only once
Dia
She
Hanya punya modal cinta
Only has love as her asset
Yang dia embuskan dalam setiap lagunya
Which she breathes into every one of her songs
Tak inginkan semua 'tuk suka dia
She doesn't want everyone to like her
Hanya ingin tuliskan lagu
She just wants to write a song
Tentang semua yang ada dalam hatinya
About everything that is in her heart
Bila tak suka tentu saja tak mengapa
If you don't like it, of course it's okay
Dia
She
Hanya punya modal cinta
Only has love as her asset
Yang dia embuskan dalam setiap lagunya
Which she breathes into every one of her songs
Tak inginkan semua 'tuk suka dia
She doesn't want everyone to like her
Hanya ingin tuliskan lagu
She just wants to write a song
Tentang semua yang ada dalam hatinya
About everything that is in her heart
Bila tak suka tentu saja tak mengapa
If you don't like it, of course it's okay
Hanya punya modal cinta
Only has love as her asset
Yang dia embuskan dalam setiap lagunya
Which she breathes into every one of her songs
Tak inginkan semua 'tuk suka dia
She doesn't want everyone to like her
Hanya ingin tuliskan lagu
She just wants to write a song
Tentang semua yang ada dalam hatinya
About everything that is in her heart
Bila tak suka tentu saja tak mengapa
If you don't like it, of course it's okay
Ioforia! Obisa! Halo!
Ioforia! Obisa! Hello!
Aku Airani Iofifteen, Iofi dari Hololive Indonesia First Generation. Halo!
I am Airani Iofifteen, Iofi from Hololive Indonesia's first generation. Hello!
Selamat datang di Birthday Live!
Welcome to the Birthday Live!
And by the way, the hashtag is #iofiLucidDream. You can just tweet all of you can, okay?
And by the way, 気付いてる人もいると思うんで、あのさっきの曲「R」がないんですよ。はい。
And by the way, I think some of you might have noticed, but that song just now didn't have any "R"s in it. Yes.
There is no R whatsoever.
Jadi kalian kalau misalkan kalian sama cadel kayak aku, kalian bisa nyanyi lagu ini karena gak ada R-nya. Ahaha!
So if you happen to have a lisp like me, you can sing this song because there are no "R"s. Ahaha!
Tapi bagi yang gak... apa ya? Bagi yang gak nyadar, nanti akan keluar versi cover song-nya.
But for those who... what is it? For those who didn't notice, a cover song version will be released later.
そのカバー曲のバージョンもあるので、後でまた見てね。
There's a cover song version of it too, so please watch it later.
Hai! It's gonna be a cover song.
And by the way, by the way, this guitar...
実はね、家でもさ、このモデルとこの色のギターもあるんですよ。見てみてください。
Actually, you know, I have this model and color of guitar at home as well. Please take a look.
Hai! If you remember, I kind of like uploaded this guitar picture somewhere. Yes.
Tapi biasanya aku main gitar cuma di membership. Iya.
But I usually only play the guitar in membership. Yes.
Jadi ini pertama kalinya aku main gitar selain di membership.
So this is the first time I'm playing the guitar outside of membership.
I usually play guitar like around in membership.
Yes, yes, yes, yes, yes...
そう、あのめんげのみんなはもう知ってると思いますけど...
So, I think everyone in the Menge already knows this...
あの、ふつうはギターはめんげでしか弾いてないんだけど、
Um, usually I only play guitar in Menge,
これがめんげじゃない配信で初めてです。
but this is the first time in a non-Menge stream.
え、ちょっと怖いんだけど、
Eh, I'm a bit nervous,
まあまあまあ、どうでしたか？
but well, well, how was it?
どう？どう？かわいい？かわいい？
How? How? Cute? Cute?
いっぱいスクショ撮った？スクショ撮った？
Did you take lots of screenshots? Screenshots?
I hope you enjoyed it!
And by the way, we still have a lot of more going on.
So after this there's gonna be a lot and a lot of guests,
so please wait for it!
この後もゲストが盛りだくさんなので、楽しみにしててくださいねー
There will be many guests after this too, so please look forward to it!
Don't forget to take a lot of screenshots!
Kawaii! Lagi? Lucu? Lucu? Lucu? Lucu?
Cute! Again? Cute? Cute? Cute? Cute?
ま、ね、時間があればこれもね、
Well, you know, if there's time,
またギター弾きたいなと思っております、はい。
I'd like to play the guitar again, yes.
あ、おっけー。
Ah, okay.
準備おっけー。
Prep is okay.
おっけー、おっけー、おっけー。
Okay, okay, okay.
では、ゲストパートにまた会おうねー！
Then, let's meet again in the guest part!
Thank you! See you in guest part!
THERE IS A REASON / Lyrics: 岩里祐穂 Music: ヒゲドライバー
THERE IS A REASON / Lyrics: Yuho Iwasato Music: Hige Driver
どこから話せばいいんだろう 待ちくたびれても
Where should I start talking, even if I'm tired of waiting
終わりだなんて言わせないから
Because I won't let you say it's the end
書き殴った無意識の衝動を連れて
Taking along the scribbled unconscious impulses
何もかも壊したら不可能を始めればいいんだ
If you break everything, you just have to start the impossible
There's a reason that we came across in this world
There's a reason that we call magnetic world
響き続け合う 世界はどこへ
Where is the world that continues to resonate with each other going
愛のために泣けるのは 君がそこにいるから
Being able to cry for the sake of love is because you are there
君だけを呼び続けるから
Because I'll keep calling only you
愛のために歌うのは そして共に生きること
Singing for the sake of love is also about living together
ずっと 君と
Forever, with you
青色した空となみひとつない鏡のよう…な
The blue sky and like a mirror without a single wave...
海を見てた
Watching the sea
どんな場所に立って どんな形になって
No matter where you stand, no matter what shape you take
どんな時代に立って
No matter what era it is,
見つけ出すよ より速く 宙吊りにした 運命に逆らって
I'll find you faster, defying the fate that was put into the air
There's a reason that we came across in this world
There's a reason that we call magnetic world
引き寄せ合う 二人はどこへ
Where are the two of us, who are drawn to each other, going
愛のために進むのは 君がそこにいるから
Moving forward for the sake of love is because you are there
僕だけが君を護るから
Because only I will protect you
愛のために願うのは そして誰も傷つけずに
Praying for the sake of love, and without hurting anyone
ずっと 隣で
Forever, by your side
僕らは超えて行く 全ての憎しみを
We will overcome all the hatred
偽物の正義など 捨ててしまえ
Throw away things like fake justice
愛のために泣けるのは 君がそこにいるから
Being able to cry for the sake of love is because you are there
We will always...
Together...
愛のために進むのは
The reason I move forward for the sake of love
君とここにいるから
Is because I am here with you
僕だけが
Because I am the only one
君を守るから
Who will protect you
愛のために願うのは
What I wish for the sake of love
そして共に生き抜くこと
Is to survive together
ずっと together
Always together
Believe...
Together...
イオフィ、お誕生日おめでとう！
Yoppi, happy birthday!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
やっと！今年も来てくれてありがとう！
We did it! Thanks for coming again this year!
え～どうもこんにちは、ときのそらです。
よろしくお願いします！
Hello, everyone, I'm Tokino Sora.
Nice to meet you!
こちら。へへへ。
And I'm over here. Hehehe.
や～なんかね、バラード歌っちゃったね。
We really sang a ballad, didn't we?
ね～
We did!
より私すごい気になってるんだけど、なんなんこの…（笑）
But more than that, I'm really curious about...
what even is this? (Laughs)
こたつ…？
A kotatsu...?
いいえ、宇宙寒いからこれ温かいよ。
No, since space is cold, this keeps us warm.
え～宇宙で焚き火なんてできるんだね。
Wow, you can actually have a campfire in space.
できるよ一応。
Well, technically you can.
だって酸素があるってことだ！
That means there's oxygen!
あ、でもでも、酸素いるからさ、
今のこれバリアいるから。
Ah, but since we need oxygen,
there's a barrier here right now.
バリアおるからね。
Because there's a barrier, you see.
酸素ないから、ないんだったらもう耐えないじゃん。
Since there's no oxygen,
we wouldn't last if we didn't have it.
あ～そうだね。そうだね。
Ah, that's true. That's true.
うん、そう。温かいよ、これ。
Right. This is warm.
イオフィさ、なんか…
You know, Yoppi...
何何？
Yes?
MCでこんなにまったり焚き火の前で、こう…
Having an MC segment where we're
relaxing in front of a campfire...
なんか夜のなんか二人で喋っちゃうみたいな雰囲気で…
...it feels like we're just two people chatting at night.
やることないよ。ないから、ちょっと変な感じがする。
We don't usually do this. It feels a bit strange.
あ～そうだね、普通にさ、ポーズしたあとにこう…
Ah, that's true. Usually, after doing a pose...
「あ！ありがとう！歌ったね！」って言うじゃん。
...we'd be like, "Ah! Thank you! We sang that!" right?
ね！すぐそうだよね。
Right! That's how it usually goes.
すぐだけど、やっぱり今年のテーマもっと緩いとかも…
It's immediate, but this year's theme is more "mellow"...
落ち着く雰囲気欲しいから、
...and I wanted a more relaxed atmosphere...
そのダンスとあの歌のあとにちょ…
...so after the dance and that song...
マイクをね、ちょっと落としてここに座ってるっていう。ね。
...we just set down the mics and sat here. You know?
でもいいね。
But it's nice.
なんかまったりできるから、ちょっとのんびりして
お喋りできる感じ、いいと思う。すごく。
Since we can relax and chat at our own pace.
I think it's really good.
やったやった！
Yay!
でね、今年誕生日にあの二回ぐらい歌んだよね。
And you know, I've had you sing for
my birthday twice already.
毎年。そう。
Every year, really.
今年…ん？去年も？
This year... wait, last year too?
あ、去年とおととしとってこと？
Ah, you mean last year and the year before?
そうそうそう。
Yes, yes, yes.
今年で、来年も来る？
So this year too. Will you come next year?
え、もちろんもちろんよ！呼んでもらえればいつでも行くよ！
Oh, of course, of course!
If you invite me, I'll come anytime!
お！やった！じゃ決定で。（笑）
Oh! Yay! Then it's decided! (Laughs)
やった～！
Yay!
そしたらなんかもうこの去年と今年も結構
ハンドマイクであのやってるから…
Since both last year and this year we've been
using hand mics...
そうだね、結構…
True, we have.
そうそう。聴かせるみたいな感じの曲ばかりだったじゃない？
They've both been the kind of songs
meant for listening, right?
じゃ来年はバリバリ踊ります？そしたら。
So, shall we dance our hearts out next year?
踊る～！
Let's dance!
うおお～！
Woah!
いいね。踊りやっぱりね、大好き。踊り。
Sounds good. I really love dancing, after all.
大好き！
I love it too!
イオフィは？
How about you, Yoppi?
好き好き好き！
I love it, love it, love it!
ね、いいよね。
Right, it's great.
や、でもさなんか今年のさテーマさっきも聞いて
バラードだって聞いて…
But you know, when I heard this year's theme
was ballads...
やっぱさバラードのさ、全体をさ、ライブするのって
すごい難しいなって私は思っちゃうの。
I really feel like doing a whole live show with only
ballads is actually quite difficult.
ほ？
Oh?
やっぱ演出とかもそうだけどさ、
The staging and everything else aside...
やっぱ私はいつもダンスとかで見せるみたいなのやるから、
...since I usually focus on "showing" through dance...
バラードで挑戦するのってすごいなって思っててさ。
...I think it's amazing to take on the challenge
of a ballad.
あ～、そう、でもなんか自分にとってはあのバラードが
あの一番声に似合うから。
Ah... well, for me, I feel ballads suit my voice the best.
あ、ね。
Ah, I see.
そう、なんかもっと見せたいな～とは思ってて。
So I've been wanting to show that more.
そ、だからね。
Yeah, so...
お、ほら見える！いっぱい！
Oh, look! There's so many!
うわ～！綺麗～宇宙！
Wow! Space is so beautiful!
宇宙に来ました。あの去年もちょっとい…
一応は宇宙にいたんだけど、
We've arrived in space. Last year we were also
technically in space...
あんまり見えないかもしれないですね。
...but you might not have been able to see it as well.
だから今年はちゃんと宇宙に行きたいですって。
So this year, I really wanted us to go to
space properly.
わ～すごい！宇宙来ました、二人で。
Wow, amazing! The two of us have come to space.
すごい！
It's amazing!
あ、綺麗本当に。
Ah, it's really beautiful.
お、なんか姉さんと似合うじゃん？
Hey, doesn't it suit you, Sora-neesan?
本当？
Really?
そう、なんか普通にイメージカラーが青だから。
Yeah, since your image color is blue.
ね。
Right.
ほら、合うの、ステージもこっちも。うん。
See, it matches both the stage and the surroundings.
え、いいな。可愛いな～。へへへ。
Hehe, that's nice. It's so cute. Hehehe.
撮った撮った！
Got them! Got them!
似合ってるでしょ？ほら、めっちゃ可愛い。
It looks good on me, right? Look, it's so cute.
ふわふわして。
It's so fluffy.
おぉ！可愛い！
Oh! How cute!
もっと見せて。
Show me more.
あ…あれ？これ私の記念日じゃないんだ。
Wait... oh? This isn't my anniversary.
そうだね。
That's right.
ヤッピー！
Yappii!
大丈夫だよ。はい。
It's okay. Here.
いっぱい撮りました。オフショ。
I took lots of photos. Off-shots.
はい、ということで今回ね、まだまだいるので、
All right, well, there's still more to come this time,
皆さんも楽しみにしてくださいね。
so everyone, please look forward to it.
ねぇ～本当におめでとうだよ！
Yeah~ really, congratulations!
では来年また歌って踊ろうね。
Then, let's sing and dance together again next year.
踊ろう！
Let's!
さあ、それでは皆さんありがとう！
Now then, thank you everyone!
ありがとうございました！
Thank you very much!
またね！バイバイ！
See you again! Bye bye!
幸せになって
Be Happy
なんども 問いかけた
I've asked myself many times
自問自答 繰り返した先に
after repeating these inner dialogues
答えが あるのなら
if there is an answer
このまま 探してみようか
shall we try searching like this?
あなたの 未来図に
In your vision of the future,
私は 少しでもいれたかな
I wonder if I was there, even a little.
あなたの いない世界は
A world without you,
想像さえ つかなかった
I couldn't even imagine it.
もしも あなたが
If you,
あの子を 選んだ瞬間に
at the moment you chose her,
私が 頭の中
if I was running through
駆け巡っていたのなら 悔しいな
your mind, that would be frustrating.
こんなにも あなたのこと
Before I ended up loving
好きになってしまう前に せめてさあ
you this much, at least...
さよならの言葉 避けてほしかったな
I wanted you to avoid those words of goodbye.
なんて勝手な わがままだよね
What a selfish thing to ask, isn't it?
誰よりも 想ってるのに
Even though I care for you more than anyone,
あなたを世界で一番笑顔に
the one who can make you smile
変えられる人は きっと私じゃないから
most in the world is surely not me.
どうか 幸せになって
Please, be happy.
どんなに 願っても
No matter how much I wish,
変わりはしない この現実が
this reality that won't change
ただただ 目の前の
just took away
光すべて 奪い去った
all the light before my eyes.
生まれ変わっても
Even if I were reborn,
もう一度 あなたに恋するかな
I wonder if I'd fall in love with you again.
そんな 妄想なんて
Even thinking about
考えることすらも 馬鹿みたい
such fantasies is foolish.
こんなにも あなたのこと
Before I ended up loving
好きになってしまう前に わざとさあ
you this much, intentionally...
優しい言葉で 勘違いさせないで
don't make me misunderstand with kind words.
なんて勝手な わがままだよね
What a selfish thing to ask, isn't it?
あなたの 幸せと笑う
Just by seeing your happy,
顔を見るだけで 胸いっぱいになる
smiling face, my heart becomes full.
あなたと私は きっとお似合いじゃないから
Because you and I surely don't suit each other,
どうか 幸せになって
please, be happy.
涙出るのは
The reason I'm crying
嘘でも 強がるから
is because I'm acting tough even if it's a lie.
気づかない ふりしないで
Don't pretend not to notice,
どうしても 諦められないよ
I just can't give up on you,
おわりだというのに
even though it's the end.
こんなにも あなたのこと
I love you so much...
好きになってしまう前に　せめてさ
Before I fall in love with you, at least...
サヨナラの言葉　告げてほしかったなんて
I wanted you to say goodbye...
勝手で我儘だよね
It's selfish and willful, isn't it?
こんなにもあなたのこと
Before I fall in love with you this much,
好きになってしまう前に　せめてさ
at least...
サヨナラの言葉　告げてほしかったなんて
I wanted you to say goodbye...
勝手で我儘だよね
It's selfish and willful, isn't it?
誰より思ってるのに　あなたを世界で
Even though I care more than anyone, you in this world...
一番笑顔に
...the one most likely to make you smile...
変えられるのはきっと
...is surely...
私じゃないから
...not me.
どうか幸せになって
Please, be happy.
幸せになって
Be happy.
あ、みんな来てくれてありがとう！
Ah, everyone, thank you for coming!
誕生日おめでとう！
Happy birthday!
ありがとう！嬉しい！イェーイ！
Thank you! I'm so happy! Yay!
嬉しい、ありがとう、おめでとう！
I'm happy, thank you, congrats!
では最初は誰から自己紹介する？
Well, first of all, who should start with the self-introductions?
んじゃ俺からいこうかな？
Then, shall I go first?
はい！
Yes!
はい、ホロスターズ1期生の律可です。よろしくお願いします！
Hi! I'm Rikka from Holostars 1st generation. Nice to meet you!
イェーイ！次は？
Yay! Next?
はい！ホロスターズグループUPROAR!!の水無世燐央です。よろしくお願いします！
Hi! I'm Minase Rio from Holostars group UPROAR!! Nice to meet you!
お願いします！
Nice to meet you!
いやーいいね、一緒に歌ってくれてありがとう！
Wow, it's nice. Thank you for singing with me!
いや、こちらこそ呼んでくれてありがとう！
No, it's us who should thank you for inviting us!
いや、嬉しかった。ありがとうございます。
I'm so happy. Thank you very much.
でね、なんか律可パイセンからは私がデビューの頃結構お世話になってて、私が。
And you know, Rikka-paisen has been taking care of me since my debut...
1周年とか来てもらったりしたもんね。
Yeah, you came to my 1st anniversary and such, right?
そうそう、なのでなんか今回歌いたいなと思ってて。
Yeah, yeah. So, I thought I really wanted to sing together this time.
ありがとね！
Thank you!
呼んでくれてありがとうね！
Thank you for inviting us!
燐央くんは...
And Rio-kun...
リオリオは。
Rio-Rio...
燐央くんは...
Rio-kun is...
後輩だもんね。
He's a junior, right?
後輩ですよ。
I am a junior.
そうそうそう。
Right, right.
なんかスタジオで会った時にさ、仕事で。たまたま休憩室でなんかこう、「じゃあ次の来年の誕生日にさ、来てくれる？」って。
When we met at the studio for work, by chance we were in the break room together and I asked, 'Hey, would you come to my next birthday [3D Live]?'
そう、言ってくれて！
Yeah, you said that!
スタジオで本当にバッタリ会って、言ってくれて、まさか本当に呼んでもらえるとは思わず...
We just happened to run into each other at the studio and you asked me. I didn't think you would really call me...
えっ！信じられなかったの？
What! You didn't believe me?
いやいや、もう嬉しすぎてビックリしちゃったよ僕。ありがとうございます。
No, no, I was just so happy and surprised. Thank you.
いいえ、いいえ、ありがとう！
No, no, thank you!
ありがとうございます。
Thank you very much.
僕たち揃うのが、あの、2年前以来だよね？
By the way, the three of us being together, it's been about two years?
久しぶりですね。
It's been a while, hasn't it?
2年前！
Two years ago!
ホロスターズ側のカウントダウンライブで、この3人とコボちゃんと4人で歌わせていただいたんですけど。
At the Holostars side's countdown live, the three of us plus Kobo-chan, the four of us sang together.
一緒に歌うのは実はそれぶり。
It's actually been that long since we sang together.
それぶり！だいぶ久しぶり。
Since then! It's been quite a while.
2年前... そう、2年前。
Two years ago... Yeah, two years ago.
もう2年経ったんだな。
Two years have passed already.
2年だなぁ。
Yeah, two years.
早いなぁ。
Time flies.
早い。早いですね。
It's fast. It's really fast.
一緒に歌えてめちゃめちゃ楽しかったです。
But singing together was really fun.
ありがとう！本当！
Thank you! Me too!
なんか3人バンドみたいだったよね。
Yeah, it felt like a three-person band.
ギター一人、ギター一人！
One guitarist, one guitarist!
ボーカルと、これ、みたいな。
And vocals and such.
見たことある感じの絵面だったよね。
It was a scene I've seen before.
来年だったらもうバンドやりますよそしたら！
Next year, let's really do a band then!
バンドね！じゃあ俺ドラムやろうかな？
A band! Then I'll do drums.
ドラム！
Drums!
そしたらなんかいい感じじゃん。
Then it'll be good.
じゃあ俺、トライアングルやるわ。
Then I'll play the triangle.
え、なんで？
Wait, why?
燐央くん何やる？
Rio-kun, what will you do?
マラカス？
Maracas?
ちょっと待って、リズム隊いらねぇって！
Wait a minute, we only have rhythm instruments!
リズム大事じゃん！
Rhythm is important!
ほとんどうるさいけど、ギターとかいないんだ。
It'll be noisy, but no guitar or anything?
え、だってトライアングルとか思わなかったの？こう、チンチンチンってするときだけ。
But the triangle's 'ting ting ting' is important when it's quiet.
確かに。
That's true.
気持ちいいよ、結構。
It feels good.
気持ちいいね。
タンバリンにしようかな。
Maybe I'll do the tambourine then.
タンバリン、タンバリン！
Tambourine, tambourine!
みんなうるさいやつじゃん。
Everyone is playing noisy instruments.
シャンシャンシャン。
Shan shan shan.
タンバリンシャンシャンシャンシャンシャン。
Tambourine shan shan shan shan shan.
今回は結構しっとりだったから。
But this song was quite mellow.
確かに。
That's true.
合うか分かんないですけどね、流石にこれはね。
I don't know if [those instruments] would fit, but...
ハモリ難しかったねやっぱり。3人だからさ。
Harmonizing was difficult after all, with three people.
そう、なんか元々、こう男性と女性が、あの、二人で歌う曲見つけるのちょっと結構難しくて。
Yeah, finding a song for two men and one woman to sing is actually quite hard.
キーがね。
The key...
そう、キーが。でも女性の曲だったらキー下げなきゃいけないし、男性だったらこっちが...
Yeah, the key. If it's a female song, the men have to lower it.
燐央くんからしたら低すぎるとか。
And if it's a male song, it's too low for you.
そう、低すぎて。だからどうしようと思って。
Yeah, it's too low. So I was wondering what to do.
でもめちゃめちゃ素敵な曲。
But it's a really wonderful song.
原曲もいいし。
The original is also nice.
ありがと、良かった。
I'm glad. Thank you.
ゲストは、この最初には、やっぱり絶対に燐央くんと律可パイセンを招待したんだけど、その時期に曲まだ決まってなくて。
When I was deciding on guests, I definitely wanted to invite Rio-kun and Rikka-paisen first, but at that time the song wasn't decided yet.
あ、そうなんだ。後から決まったんだ。
Oh, really? It was decided later?
後から。そう、後から。
Later, yeah.
いいの見つけたね。
You found a good one.
ありがと！本当によかったよ。声も合ってたし、この3人の。うん。
Thank you! I'm really glad. It matched the three of us' voices too.
めちゃめちゃよかった。本当によかった。
It was really good. It was really good.
ゲストが、ゲストが、決まって、その曲って感じね。
So, the guests were decided first, then the song.
なるほどね。
I see.
またやりたいけどね。
I want to do it again sometime.
やりたい！
I want to!
歌、また...
Let's sing again...
ねえ、次はバンド？
Hey, next a band?
バンドやるか！
Let's do a band!
バンド。イオフィマラカス。
Band. Iofi maracas.
練習時間めちゃかかりそうだけどね。
Seems like it'll take a lot of practice time though.
確かに。イオフィドラムやったことないからね。
True. Since Iofi hasn't played drums before.
やるの？やるしかない！
Doing it? We have no choice but to do it!
やるなら練習しますよ。
If we're doing it, I'll practice.
あ、じゃあ来年やります、バンド。
Ah, then we'll do it next year, the band.
楽しみ！
Looking forward to it!
もうイオフィったら本当にやりそうだから。
Geez, Iofi, you really look like you'd do it.
怖い。
Scary.
ということで来年楽しみにしていてくださいね。
So please look forward to next year.
絶対に、本当に怖い... みんな本気にするよ。
Definitely, really scary... everyone will take it seriously.
みんな本気にしちゃうよこれ。
Everyone will take this seriously.
怖い怖い。
Scary, scary.
じゃあ来年楽しみということで。
Then, looking forward to next year.
本当に皆見てくれてありがとう。これからもね、まだまだあるので。
Truly, thank you everyone for watching. There's still more to come.
まだまだあるので。
There's still more.
うん、楽しんでください。
Yeah, please enjoy.
楽しんでー！おめでとー！またねー！ありがとー！楽しんでねー！
Enjoy! Congratulations! See you! Thank you! Enjoy!
ぼくらのレットイットビー
Our Let It Be
生まれ変われるのなら
If we could be reborn
目印になるから前を向いてよ
I'll be your landmark, so look forward
小指と小指の長い糸
The long thread between our pinkies
解けないように結んだの
I tied it so it wouldn't come undone
夏祭り 夜雨降り
Summer festival, night rain falls
空に虹が掛かる
A rainbow appears in the sky
頃なの
It's around that time
壊れた感情じゃ いつか君を消してゆく
With broken emotions, I'll eventually erase you
見えなくなると失われる灯火
A light that is lost when it becomes invisible
でも結んだ長い糸 ほどけ落ちていないから
But the long thread we tied hasn't come undone
また僕たちは出会う時が来る きっと
So the time will come for us to meet again, surely
僕ら大人になったら
When we grow up
正義のヒーローになるんだ
We'll become heroes of justice
地球の平和を守るのさ
We'll protect the peace of the Earth
探検しようぜ お化け屋敷
Let's explore the haunted house
でも本当は怖くて 泣き虫
But actually I'm scared, a crybaby
一緒にいたいだけ
I just want to be together
明日は晴れて 空を仰いで照らせば
If it's sunny tomorrow and the sky shines as we look up
僕らはここに秘密基地を作ろう
Let's build a secret base here
そして探検しよう
And let's explore
雨ならゲームしよう
If it rains, let's play games
そんな時間が ずっと続くはずだったんだ そう
Such times were supposed to last forever, yes
悪かったのは僕だった
The one who was wrong was me
逃げ出したのは僕だった
The one who ran away was me
嘘じゃない本当の嘘つきだ
It's not a lie, I'm a real liar
花束に包まれて 目を瞑る君は
Wrapped in a bouquet, you who closed your eyes
安らかに 清らかに 眠っていたんだ
Were sleeping peacefully and purely
壊れた感情が
Broken emotions
いつか君を消してゆこう
Will eventually erase you
失う前に
Before losing
消えてしまう前に
Before disappearing
ただ結んだ長い糸 ほどけ落ちていなかった
The long thread we just tied hadn't come undone
きっと僕たちは...
Surely we...
...さと時が降る
...and time descends
きっと
Surely
Pandangan Pertama
First Sight
Lama ku memendam rasa di dada
I've been harboring these feelings in my chest
Mengagumi indahmu wahai jelita
Admiring your beauty, oh gorgeous
Tak dapat lagi ku ucap kata
I can no longer say a word
Bisuku diam terpesona
My silence, stunned in awe
Dan andai suatu hari kau jadi milikku
And if one day you become mine
Tak akan ku lepas dirimu oh kasih
I won't let you go, oh my love
Dan bila waktu mengizinkanku untuk menunggu dirimu
And if time allows me to wait for you
Kurasa ku t'lah jatuh cinta
I think I've fallen in love
Pada pandangan yang pertama
At first sight
Sulit bagiku untuk bisa
It's hard for me to be able to
Berhenti mengagumi dirinya
Stop admiring her
Seiring dengan berjalannya waktu
As time goes by
Akhirnya kita berdua bertemu
Finally, the two of us meet
Oh diriku tersipu malu
Oh, I'm blushing
Melihat sikapmu yang lucu
Seeing your cute behavior
Dan andai suatu hari kau jadi milikku
And if one day you become mine
Tak akan ku lepas dirimu oh kasih
I won't let you go, oh my love
Dan bila waktu mengizinkanku untuk menunggu dirimu
And if time allows me to wait for you
Kurasa ku t'lah jatuh cinta
I think I've fallen in love
Pada pandangan yang pertama
At first sight
Sulit bagiku untuk bisa
It's hard for me to be able to
Berhenti mengagumi dirinya
Stop admiring her
Oh Tuhan tolong diriku
Oh Lord, please help me
Tuk membuat dia menjadi milikku
To make her mine
Sayangku, kasihku, oh cintaku
My darling, my dear, oh my love
She's all that I need
Dan bila kita bersama
And when we are together
Kan ku jaga dirimu untuk selamanya
I will protect you forever
Oh terima cintaku
Oh, accept my love
Summertime, ain't a summertime
if I don't have you as mine,
but you're always on my mind, yeah.
In the magazine you showed up
baby girl your beauty makes my mind blow up.
Your personality's calm and friendly
the kinda girl that I would love to be with me.
Once I start, no I won't fall back
here's my cellphone number
so please call back, come on!
Kurasa ku t'lah jatuh cinta
I think I've fallen in love
Pada pandangan yang pertama
At first sight
Sulit bagiku untuk bisa
It's hard for me to be able to
Berhenti mengagumi dirinya
Stop admiring her
Oh Tuhan tolong diriku
Oh Lord, please help me
Tuk membuat dia menjadi milikku
To make her mine
Sayangku, kasihku, oh cintaku
My darling, my dear, oh my love
She's all that I need
Pesawat Kertas 365 Hari
365-Day Paper Plane
Kutatapan langit di pagi hari
I gaze at the sky in the morning
Kuawali hari dengan doa
I start the day with a prayer
Semoga satu hari ini bisa
Hoping that this one day can
Dipenuhi oleh senyum
Be filled with smiles
Walau pun terkadang hujan turun
Even though sometimes rain falls
Dan air mata juga mengalir
And tears also flow
Di hari yang tak berjalan dengan mulus
On days that don't go smoothly
Besok pun tetap semangat
I'll still stay spirited for tomorrow
Di dalam mimpiku selalu
In my dreams, I always
Terlihat ada diriku sendiri
See myself
Yang dengan bebasnya melakukan semua
Freely doing everything
Hal yang ingin aku lakukan
The things I want to do
Hidup bagaikan pesawat kertas
Life is like a paper plane
Terbang dan pergi membawa impian
Flying and going, carrying dreams
Sekuat tenaga dengan hembusan angin
With all its might, with the gust of wind
Terus melaju terbang
It continues to speed and fly
Jangan bandingkan jarak terbangnya
Don't compare how far it flies
Tapi bagaimana dan apa yang dilalui
But how and what it went through
Karena itulah satu hal yang penting
Because that's the one important thing
Selalu sesuai kata hati
To always follow your heart
Sanbyaku rokujuugonichi
Three hundred and sixty-five days
Di saat terlihat bintang-bintang
At the time the stars are visible
Atau malam yang gelap gulita
Or the pitch-black night
Pada saat semangatmu hilang, carilah
When your spirit is gone, look for
Orang lain dan bicaralah
Another person and speak
Manusia tidaklah pernah
Humans are never
Ditinggal sendirian saja
Left all alone
Terkadang kita tak menyadari
Sometimes we don't realize
Hal baik di sekitar kita
The good things around us
Hidup bagaikan pesawat kertas
Life is like a paper plane
Terbang dan membawa cinta kita semua
Flying and carrying all our love
Sayap yang terbentang dengan percaya diri
Wings spread wide with confidence
Dilihat semua orang
Seen by everyone
Walau tak tahu cara melipatnya
Even if you don't know how to fold it
Suatu saat pasti akan berhasil lalu terbang
One day it will surely succeed and then fly
Kekuatan harapan yang menerbangkannya
The power of hope that makes it fly
Ya, mari mimpi lebih lah
Yes, let's dream even more
Sanbyaku rokujuugonichi
Three hundred and sixty-five days
Hidup bagaikan pesawat kertas
Life is like a paper plane
Terbang dan pergi membawa impian
Flying and going, carrying dreams
Sekuat tenaga dengan hembusan angin
With all its might, with the gust of wind
Terus melaju terbang
It continues to speed and fly
Jangan bandingkan jarak terbangnya
Don't compare how far it flies
Tapi bagaimana dan apa yang dilalui
But how and what it went through
Karena itulah satu hal yang penting
Because that's the one important thing
Selalu sesuai kata hati
To always follow your heart
Sanbyaku rokujuugonichi
Three hundred and sixty-five days
Ayo terbanglah!
Come on, fly!
Coba terbanglah!
Try to fly!
lah...
ay...
Ayo terbanglah
Come on, let's fly
Coba terbanglah
Try to fly
Ayo terbanglah
Come on, let's fly
Coba terbanglah
Try to fly
Ayo terbanglah
Come on, let's fly
Coba terbanglah
Try to fly
(Tertawa) Aku dapat!
(Laughing) I got it!
Yey! Halo semuanya!
Yay! Hello everyone!
Oh my god, look at me dong.
Oh my god, look at me.
Hai!
Hi!
Akhirnya ya Pia, collab kecil-kecilan kita...
Finally Pia, our small-scale collab...
...gak kecil, udah jadi besar guys!
...isn't small, it's become huge guys!
Yey! Finally! Oh my god!
Yay! Finally! Oh my god!
Finally!
Terima kasih sudah...
Thank you for...
Eh ini berdiri deh.
Let's stand up.
Jadi... terima kasih sudah mengundang saya, Senpai.
So... thank you for inviting me, Senpai.
Oit, Senpai!
Oh, Senpai!
Iya, Senpai.
Yes, Senpai.
Berapa sudah ulang tahun yang ke berapa Senpai?
How old are you, which birthday is it Senpai?
Enam!
Six!
Tapi kok belum lulus-lulus juga? (Tertawa)
But why haven't you graduated yet? (Laughs)
Ssst... daripada gitu mending jikoshoukai dulu.
Shhh... instead of that, let's do self-introductions first.
Oh iya, iya.
Oh right, right.
We are on fire!
Semangat membara yang menghangatkan hari-harimu.
A blazing spirit that warms your days.
Halo aku Pia Meraleo dari JKT48 Virtual...
Hello, I'm Pia Meraleo from JKT48 Virtual...
...generasi pertama. Halo semuanya!
...first generation. Hello everyone!
Anyway, aku nyadar sesuatu, tahu enggak?
Anyway, I realized something, you know?
Apa?
What?
So, basically buat kalian yang bilang aku pendek...
So, basically for those of you who say I'm short...
...now you guys see.
Hah, dikit doang!
Hah, only by a little!
Dikit doang means everything to me, you know?
Only a little means everything to me, you know?
Oke, duduk aja yuk.
Okay, let's just sit down.
Well for your information, itu gak banyak kok.
Well for your information, it's not much.
Paling 18 centimeter.
Probably only 18 centimeters.
Tapi kaki aku gak nyampe.
But my feet don't reach.
Lihat.
Look.
Look at that, ngambang cuy!
Look at that, it's floating, man!
Bro, lihat, ngambang for no reason.
Bro, look, it's floating for no reason.
Ya Pia, itu bedanya.
Yeah Pia, that's the difference.
これ、私、これ、見て！届かない！
This! Me! This! Look! It doesn't reach!
Okelah.
Okay then.
Jadi untuk lagu ini ya, anyway...
So for this song, anyway...
...koreografinya Fritz-kun.
...the choreography is by Fritz-kun.
Aku dikasih tahu sama Pia, ピアから教えてもらいました。
I was told by Pia, Pia taught me.
Kayak gini.
Like this.
これ、これ、これ、これ。
This, this, this, this.
Itu favorit banget gak sih?
Isn't that a total favorite?
Kawaii.
Cute.
Iya kawaii.
Yes, cute.
Lucu banget kan?
It's so cute, right?
Guys, please don't judge me.
We're learning, okay? We're learning, oh.
Iya, we're learning, jadi kalau ada yang apa-apa, ke Pia.
Yes, we're learning, so if anything happens, blame Pia.
Gak gitu ya! Gak gitu!
Not like that! Not like that!
Anyway, what is this?
Karena kamu mau ke sini, aku persiapin ini.
Since you were coming here, I prepared this.
Really?
Is this like for me?
We are on fire!
Bau gue?
Smells like me?
Jadi kalau kalian penasaran, ini baunya Pia kayak gini, guys.
So if you're curious, this is what Pia smells like, guys.
Bau arang, bau abu, bau arang itu bau gue cuy.
Smell of charcoal, smell of ash, charcoal is my scent, man.
Ini lucu banget, oh my god, kore wa...
This is so cute, oh my god, this is...
Aku suka banget, Kak.
I love it so much, Kak.
Gak mau pulang boleh gak?
Can I not go home?
Gak mau pulang, atau gue di sini jadi tukang kabel juga gak apa-apa deh.
I don't want to go home, or I could just be a cable technician here, that's fine too.
Iya, terima kasih untuk managernya Pia...
Yes, thank you to Pia's manager...
...sudah meminjamkan saya Pia.
...for lending me Pia.
Pia-chan arigatou buat staff-san, M-chan arigatou.
Pia-chan thank you, to the staff, M-chan thank you.
Oshiku, akhirnya aku bisa manggil kamu, tahu enggak?
My oshi, finally I can call you, you know?
Aku tuh guys waktu pertama kali dibilang aku mau invite kamu...
When I was first told that I was going to be invited by you...
Nani? Wah!
What? Wow!
Aku sampai managerku kayak, 'Kalau bisa kupegang, wah!'
I told my manager like, 'If I could hold her, wow!'
Wah, aku diundang sama oshiku.
Wow, I was invited by my oshi.
Tapi aku walaupun excited harus pulang, Bro.
But even though I'm excited, I have to go home, Bro.
Oh iya bener, oh thank you for coming.
Oh right, oh thank you for coming.
Enjoy the rest of the show. I will watch from there.
Bye-bye! Arigatou! Thank you!
Bye-bye! Thank you! Thank you!
Oke, kita sudah di penghujung acara nih guys.
Okay, we're at the end of the show guys.
Tapi sebelum kita ke akhir acara, aku akan berterima kasih dulu.
But before we get to the end, I'll say some thanks first.
Terima kasih sudah datang.
Thank you for coming.
Torane-sama arigatou, Depasu-mo arigatou...
Torane-sama thank you, Depasu-mo thank you...
...Ryo-kun mo arigatou, Pia juga terima kasih...
...Ryo-kun also thank you, and thanks to Pia too...
Benar, terima kasih semuanya.
That's right, thank you everyone.
Iya, akhirnya ya, Iofi's Birthday Celebration 2025 sudah di penghujung acara.
Yes, finally, Iofi's Birthday Celebration 2025 is at the end of the show.
Tapi jangan skip-skip dulu!
But don't skip yet!
Sebelum berakhir, aku punya sesuatu untuk kalian.
Before it ends, I have something for you.
でわ、Birthday Goods... たったーん! ぶっぶん!
Now, Birthday Goods... tadaaa! Bam!
Hai, Iofi's Birthday 2025.
Hi, Iofi's Birthday 2025.
Kita punya 3 merch dan sesuatu yang spesial dan voice.
We have 3 merch items, something special, and a voice pack.
Mari kita lihat ya, とんたん!
Let's take a look, ta-da!
Hai, ioDreaming Blanket. I'll keep you warm 24/7.
Hi, ioDreaming Blanket. I'll keep you warm 24/7.
イオフィが暖かく包んであげるよ。
Iofi will wrap you up warmly.
こうやって、ぎゅっとね。温かいからね。
Like this, a big hug. Because it's warm.
Jadi kalau kalian aduh dingin, perlu ditemani hangat ini,
So if you're cold and need some warm company,
aku akan menemani malam-malammu yang dingin.
I will accompany you through your cold nights.
で、今年もイラストは夜ノみつきママ! ありがとう!
And this year's illustration is by Mitsuki Mama again! Thank you!
皆様もママありがとう! わー!
Everyone's mama, thank you! Wow!
Lucu sekali, ふわふわ、かわいい。
It's so cute, fluffy, and cute.
Et tapi kalau sudah ada blanket berarti kurang apa sih?
But if you have a blanket, what else is missing?
Ah, next up!
We have this one! Sweet Dreams Pillow Cover.
Iya, ah...
Yes, ah...
Jadi ini selain...
So this is besides...
tapi kayaknya kepala kalian bisa pas buat di... ehehe.
but it seems like your heads would fit perfectly in... hehe.
Basically, it's so fluffy, it's so comfy.
You can place your head right in... yeah, ehehe.
あの、これいいでしょ、こうやって。
Um, this is good, right? Like this.
は、そうそう。
Ha, yeah, yeah.
あ、でもでもでも、イオフィに夢中すぎてちょっと時間忘れちゃう。
Oh, but, but, but, if you get too absorbed in Iofi that you forget the time.
あ、やばいどうしようっていうときはこちらです!
Ah no, what should I do? In that case, here it is!
Hai! Jadi kalian kalau punya ini nggak akan lupa waktu.
Hi! So if you have this, you won't forget the time.
Aduh aku terlalu fokus sama Iofi, aku lupa waktu, oh my God!
"Oh, I'm too focused on Iofi, I forgot the time, oh my God!"
Ini!
This!
So you won't really forget about time while thinking about me.
あははは! かわいいでしょ?
Ahahaha! Isn't it cute?
はい! あ、でもでもでも、次次次次、次は...
Yes! Ah but but but, next, next, next, next...
なんだなんだ? あ、こちらです!
what is it? Ah, here it is!
はい、どうぞ!
Yes, please!
Gini kita bisa ketemu di dalam mimpi.
This way we can meet in a dream.
Situational Voice Pack "Dream Rendezvous" so you will be meeting me in a dream.
そう夢でも会えるように、このボイスを聴いてね!
So so that we can meet even in dreams, please listen to this voice pack!
はい!
Yes!
では、あの... 日本語、インドネシア語と英語、三つです!
Now, um... Japanese, Indonesian, and English, there are three!
はい、みんな聴いてね!
Yes, everyone please listen!
ででで、今年が新しいのよ、私の出てくるのよ。
And, and, and, this year there's something new, I'm coming out.
There's gonna be something new this year and this is it! Pam!
There's gonna be something new this year and this is it! Bam!
If you buy the full version, there's gonna be hololive OFFICIAL CARD GAME PR card!
Yeay! This is a bonus hololive card.
Ini sebagai bonus pemberian full set premium, premium merchandise.
This is a bonus for the premium full set purchase, premium merchandise.
Akan tambahan bonus kartu yang bisa kalian pakai di gamenya official hololive card, yes!
There's an additional bonus card that you can use in the hololive Official Card Game, yes!
You can actually use it on the game, yeah.
これでさ、大会とかで使ったらさ、めっちゃ自慢できますよ。
With this, if you use it in tournaments or something, you can really brag.
こうやって、 「うわ、これがイオフィの限定の誕生日グッズから出たんや。」
Like this, "Whoa, this came from Iofi's limited birthday goods."
ほい!
Hey!
でもまあお守りとしてもね、ここに置いてても大丈夫ですよ。
But well, even as a lucky charm, it's okay to keep it here.
イオフィはここにいるから。
Because Iofi is right here.
えへへへ!
Ehehehe!
Yeah!
Jadi ini bonus bisa dipakai di kartu ya di gamenya official hololive card
So this bonus card can be used in the Hololive Official Card Game,
tapi kartunya hari ini yang ini sayang sekali baru ada bahasa Jepangnya jadi mohon pengertiannya ya.
but unfortunately, this one is only available in Japanese for now, so please understand.
Untuk detail kartu dan cara bermain bisa dicek di homepage.
For card details and how to play, you can check the homepage.
Begitu guys, terima kasih!
That's it guys, thank you!
Dan kita sudah sampai di penghujung-ujung-ujung-ujung acara.
And we've reached the very, very, very end of the show.
Mmm, jadi karena tahun lalu kita sudah dengar "Here I Am" yang biasa...
Mmm, since last year we heard the regular "Here I Am"...
nah tahun ini aku punya yang spesial untuk kalian.
well, this year I have something special for you.
"Here I Am" full bahasa Indonesia!
"Here I Am" full in Indonesian!
Hai! "Here I Am" Indonesian version.
Yes! "Here I Am" Indonesian version.
Tapi itu hanya untuk membership.
But that's only for membership.
や、メンバーシップ限定で "Here I Am" インドネシア語バージョン後で歌います。
Yes, I'll sing the Indonesian version of "Here I Am" later in a membership-only stream.
Hai!
Yes!
Jadi habis ini akan apa ya?
So after this, what's next?
Aku akan ketemu kalian di membership, oke?
I'll see you guys in membership, okay?
でわ、本当の本当の本当の最後の曲になります。 はい!
Now, it's time for the truly, truly, truly last song. Yes!
This will be my last song for tonight.
I hope you're ready.
This last song will be...
心の坂道
Heart's Sloped Path
手話で。
In sign language.
何度も苦しい思いをした
I've been through pain more times than I can say
何度も悲しい思いもした
I've felt the sorrow that wouldn't go away
今日までたくさん歩いてきた
Step by step, I've made it here today
心の坂道を (坂道を)
Up the hill where my feelings lay (Up the hill)
歩き慣れた帰り道
I tripped and fell on the road I always take
のぞせむ転んだ
Caught off guard,
不意打ちみたいで
like a sudden break
まるで裏切られた気分
It hit me like a stab in the back
破けちゃったジーンズと
In torn-up jeans and
心の隙間に
a heart with a crack,
冷たい風が抜ける
The cold wind gently passes through.
小石蹴飛ばして一歩
I kick a pebble as I move on too.
踏み出すとき君が
The moment I take a single step ahead,
いてくれてたんだ
I found you standing there instead.
何度も苦しい思いをした
I've been through pain more times than I can say,
何度も悲しい思いもした
I've felt the sorrow that wouldn't go away.
今日までたくさん歩いてきた
Step by step, I've made it here today.
心の坂道は
Up the hill where my feelings lay...
君がいたから強くなれた
Because you were there for me, I found the strength to be.
傷だらけでもあの坂も歩けた
Even with scars, I climbed that hill with ease.
君がいるから歩いて行けるさ
Because you're here with me, I know I'll keep walking free.
涙の足跡残さないで
Leaving no trails for the world to see.
あの日君は言ってた
That day, you said to me,
本当の強さは泣いてもまた笑えることだよ
True strength is being able to cry, then smile again, you know?
何度も苦しい思いをした
I've been through pain more times than I can say,
何度も悲しい思いもした
I've felt the sorrow that wouldn't go away.
今日までたくさん歩いてきた
Step by step, I've made it here today.
心の坂道は
Up the hill where my feelings lay...
君がいたから強くなれた
Because you were there for me, I found the strength to be.
傷だらけでもあの坂も歩けた
Even with scars, I climbed that hill with ease.
君がいるから歩いて行けるさ
Because you're here with me, I know I'll keep walking free.
涙の足跡残さないで
Leaving no trails for the world to see.
君がいたから
Because you were there for me...
君がいるから
Because you're here with me...